[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
[Music]
i just wanted to confirm were you
waiting for me to begin uh
yes i thought you were going to oh i was
whispy or something
i thought though you were gonna open the
space but uh okay i
i will open the space okay so wow
[Laughter]
i'm just having a good time sitting here
waiting uh
welcome everybody um this is i don't
know the second and third
well i guess i've been i've shown up on
the stoa a number of times this is the
first time in this context
and it's been actually pretty exciting
for me to
reconnect to something i spent quite a
number of years
researching and i guess reflecting on as
i went through the journey of being an
entrepreneur i worked with a fellow
named
dane who had a foundation that taught
entrepreneurial skills
and one of the core
interventions that we ended up offering
for that was
the opportunity to give people some
really
deep insights into how their own
emotional history was limiting
their success as an entrepreneur
and that turned out to be a little bit
of a highlight of the program
uh for the time that i was there and i
also did some interesting research
on um the personality characteristics of
entrepreneurs
uh we had about a hundred people who had
applied to be part of the foundation
now peter are you able to admit people
or do i need to keep doing that
you'll do it i'll do it yeah awesome
there's two people there
um and and we did
some really interesting research uh
whenever i get involved in data analysis
i tend to find
uh odd odd and interesting ways of
approaching stuff
and uh i came up with an interesting
analysis
where we had about a hundred hundred and
fifty uh i forget the numbers people who
were in the training program who took
the hexaco which is the five factor
personality scale with about
20 subscales and we also managed to get
about
20 graduates of the program who had
actually closer to 30 who had become
successes
who had made millions of dollars um
and so instead of just looking at their
profiles and seeing how they compared
to ordinary people which we just do by
looking
at normative data for the hexagon we
actually compared
their subscale scores with the what
with the aspiring entrepreneurs
and found that there was actually
10 of the 30 or whatever sub scales that
really predicted
who would become successful and we'll
spend a little bit of time on that but
what's what's interesting about it is
that when we look closely at the
subscales there was very
clearly emotional components to things
so one of the stuff one of the things
about when i
talk or teach or uh do these kinds of
inter
these kinds of programs i really love to
have
audience participation because it guides
me into
speaking in ways that are relevant to
you guys so
uh in a way that we can i can see half
the screen here
uh if i um if everyone who can
puts on their um their screens you know
so that i can just see you i'm gonna go
full screen for a second
um how many of you are actively involved
in being entrepreneurs right now
if you just you know put up your hand
okay quite a bit um in fact almost
everybody that i can see on my screen
um and how many of you have come to the
realization
and i'm gonna paraphrase this and maybe
over emphasize it
that you're your own worst enemy
all right then you are my target
audience i i think you're really going
to resonate
with what i'm talking about um
i'm going to pull over to my my rome
notes and just glance and make sure i
stay
on topic here um
one of the things that i think if you
know my work
i'm very much interested in
transformation
and i work within what i call the four
facets of transformation
which i used to think was a spiritual
um kind of context but now i really see
that it's very much of a
personal growth transformation that
there's
from this framework there are four
distinct dimensions that we all have to
go through
to become really complete and
well-welded human beings
and when i have spent my time
as a clinician for the last 20 25 years
and then as a life coach
i've come to appreciate that there were
i would say three
archetypal paths of transformation in
our culture right now
and one of them is the the explicitly
spiritual path where you go to a
monastery or you commit to a deep
practice and you make that a major part
of your life
and it will transform you
the other path that i've
really come to appreciate and i would
say has been a large component of my
path
because unlike what i thought i didn't
become a priest or a monastic i
i ended up getting married which
surprised the hell out of me um
but that second path is a deeply
committed relationship whether it's a
marriage or not
where you use the friction of
and the tension between the two of you
as
cues for transformation so
to me for people who are really
interested in deep transformation on all
four facets not just the first one
but all four facets
a relationship path is probably more
intense than a monastic path
okay the monastic path is really good
for waking up
the
relationship path is really good for
cleaning up because all your emotional
baggage will get activated
you know in a long-term relationship and
it will help you with the growing up
which is the third facet
and in the process you will disidentify
from a lot of these dimensions which is
the waking up path it's
probably the relationship path is not
enough to take you all the way to the
enlightenment
pinnacle of the waking up piece but
it'll take you a long way
in terms of becoming a functional human
being and
the fourth dimension the fourth facet
that i work within is
the um i don't ken wilber talks about it
is the showing up in the world
and i actually see showing up as a
developmental stage
i i think the fourth facet is actually
the um looking around or what are you
sensitive to so if you're in a
relationship
and you're oblivious to interpersonal
body language
or emotions and and subtle
you know non-verbal cues if you're
oblivious to that
you're gonna have a difficult time
having a healthy relationship with your
partner or anybody
right and so the fourth facet is really
becoming sensitive to
all of the dimensions that we are
capable of perceiving as human beings
and if you're into the shamanistic world
that includes exploring the subtle
realms
astral travel lucid dreaming shamanic
journeying
waking up to those other realms okay but
it also has a very tangible
applied thing of just being sensitive to
the world around you and picking up all
the cues that you can to process them in
your relationships and
your journey so we've got the monastic
path
we've got the relationship path and i
would say the uh
yeah peter that's it it's the the
showing i i would
not it's not the integrating uh it's the
um i
integrated um i call it perceptual loci
or or um you could say showing
up to all dimensions but that's a
different
way of meaning it than ken welder means
it so
we've got the monastic path we've got
the relationship path and i would say
the third archetypal path that's being
used for transformation when you look at
people like
tony robbins and evan pagan is the
entrepreneurial path
that if you notice so many of those
workshops on entrepreneurial success
have deep levels of personal and
transformational growth exercises in
them
and what we're going to do is look at
why that is
and one of the reasons that i like the
entrepreneurial path
is that as you do this work and this is
what i evidenced as i worked with people
at uh danes foundation
people who did their work got past the
blocks they needed for a particular
stage
of the entrepreneurial path that they
couldn't make it
through and once they got past the block
and they made it past the stage
money started coming in or their
networking started increasing and it
translated into fiscal success fairly
quickly
because a lot of these people had done a
lot of the stages and were just stuck
at one place and once they opened that
kind of bottleneck
the whole pipeline started flowing and
money started coming in so like
what an awesome bonus that not only do
you get an increased
quality of life but you get like
you get it reflected in the success of
your business ventures so
i'm gonna pause there and just ask for
questions on anything that i've said so
i get a sense of
how this is resonating and what's making
sense to you guys and then we'll move on
to
what i pulled up is the five stages of
an entrepreneurial movement towards
success in starting a business so
why don't some of you uh ask some
questions or tell me how this is landing
on you
would you like them to unmute themselves
or put in the trap off yeah
you can unmute yourself we'll go popcorn
style or if you want to raise your hand
i can get it in the participants list um
and we can go that way but we'll try
popcorn style unless it gets to be too
hard to keep up with okay
so on john has something that chats it
seems like he just wants a clarification
question so there are three paths and
four ways
up in that that's his question
yeah yeah uh the three paths that
the monastic the uh the relational and
the entrepreneurial
they seem to be the archetypes right now
in our culture
you know for deep transformation and
where there's lots of resources being
devoted to it
um george yeah if you want to just
unmute and speak okay i guess what in
regards to the showing up to all
dimensions
is that something that you seek out or
that is that something that you just
take on as you
uh as you experience uh different
uh dimensions uh
my experience has been as as you do like
you can do that path
explicitly um and and i kind of refer to
that as the shamanistic path
uh but it doesn't that doesn't
necessarily capture the
um you know think of an autistic person
and
their inability to process cues because
they just don't see them
so to the extent that you're missing
cues
you're going to get friction in your
life that's going to wake you up to
attending to them the other thing that
seems to happen is as
people do enough cleaning up and growing
them
their sensitivity naturally increases
and their curiosity
increases and these other dimensions
start just emerging naturally
and that's probably the safest way to do
the shamanistic path
you know especially if you're going to
be getting into the lucid dreaming
and uh you know the dream yogas and
and all the other worlds that are
involved or taking ethniogems and
you know moving into apparently other
realms of existence
thank you
andrew you unread yourself oh yeah
um i think that you uh mentioned this
i'm so curious about like the facets of
transformation and i was like
uh about like your thoughts on autism
and having a transformation through
relationships and
my instant thought was it's almost
explained to steve
jobs it almost explains
like the kind of pathology um
that he has that he has gone through i'm
just curious about like if you can
elaborate more
on on that um i
actually don't know steve jobs life well
enough to speak to that and i'm
certainly not going to speak to
general transformations of autistic
people i just don't have enough
experience with it yeah but
but to the extent i mean one of the
beauty beautiful things about the brain
is the neuroplasticity we know that if
you
you know people who've had strokes if
they and in the past
could never recover if they really pay
attention and
you know work through it a slow
step-by-step
path for learning the
processes that had been lost through the
stroke that they will grow
new neural tissue or use other existing
tissue
to start handling that process and so
i've watched there's actually a great
program in toronto
where people are recovering way higher
levels
of um competence in areas that they had
been
that they had lost uh as a result of
this very systematic training program
that
that's focused on developing new neurons
how far you can take that you know i i
really don't know
in terms of autism or what or whatever
oh okay yeah thank you that was
insightful thanks
all right so douglas thanks for doing
this uh
i like hearing these three different
ways of doing it and i i think
these days a lot of us are having a lot
of challenges around
the feedback we get from direct market
activity
and that we're seeing the
finances as not a great measure of
what we want to create in the world i'm
certainly speaking for myself
and i'm just wondering if you have any
insights around how to better be a
social entrepreneur or conscious
capitalist in this to
integrate all three of these together or
to to
see some other dimensions of the
activity that we do that still provides
a livelihood but maybe through more
social capital or through other forms of
capital
that um that we know are supporting our
communities and
inevitably our our world uh our global
global uh ecological systems and so
forth that's a great question daryl and
uh and i would
you know my first response is that uh we
we best see that which we measure so i
pulled out
money as a measurement because everyone
measures with money but if you
if your value system is different and
you're gonna measure social impact
i mean and i've done interventions for
rehabilitation and the first thing you
have to do is define your outcomes
and start measuring them and then you
can get feedback as to whether your
interventions or what you're doing
is affecting them so whatever you're
interested in whatever it is you value
you should start measuring and finding
ways to assess it and use that as
feedback
as you move towards your goal um
i actually have a blog post that i
haven't released yet because i haven't
released any but i've got probably three
or four
pretty in-depth ones written um and
it's just not time to release them yet
where i'm
challenging people to to to start
contemplating the notion
of um emotional prosperity
where so much of our lives have been
spent on fiscal or financial prosperity
often to buy activities we think that
will lead
to like health and well-being but
most of our deeply most deeply ingrained
feel-good experiences are relational
and so if you get rid of the
intermediary
of money once i have money i can do that
or
we can go on that trip or we can
experience this thing together
and start looking at emotional
prosperity
you can see how you can in many
situations go directly to what it is
you're valuing
without needing to spend lots of money
on it and that means investing
in your emotional well-being and your
interpersonal relationships to the point
where they start
generating emotional well-being for you
it's it's a it's an emotional prosperity
and capital that i think
from a post-modern perspective is what
we're actually yearning for as a culture
we just don't have a framework to to
understand that yet
so yeah go ahead well i was just going
to close off and move to the next
section but if
you wanted to say something that would
be great agreeing that
it's these other things are more
intangible and i look forward to
new metrics that are able to better
measure our
carbon footprint and probably there's a
lot better better things to measure
and i look forward to your blog when it
comes out sounds like a great
point thanks so what i'm going to do now
is
i'm going to come up i i pulled out a uh
a blog that someone had written on um
the five critical stages you'll go
through as an entrepreneur by stan
uh edom and i i picked him only because
he was the most
popular one on the search engine there's
a lot of different ways to cut the
stages
um i would probably have put them into
quadrants and things like that
but this is probably the most accessible
and as we go through the stages i want
you to relate to which stage you're
in which stage you feel like you've
completed
and which stages maybe you're
stalling at and we're probably going to
get a little bit of discussion
in that context and then i'm going to
have you guys complete
an actual um entrepreneurial assessment
that i put together
where you'll focus on the place where
you're bottlenecked
and we're going to look for some of the
core feelings that emerge
and when i refer to core feelings that's
part of my framework where i believe
we're
genetically biologically programmed to
experience
ourselves in relationship to the world
and in relationship to other people on
these nine
core dimensions which we experience as
feelings so i can
feel significant or insignificant
to my partner or to the world or to my
uh job or you know to you people
and how i feel will greatly
impact on how i show up to the world or
how i show up
to the relationship and unfortunately
often the so there's that's an example
of insignificant there's helpless
inadequate potent and powerful versus
helpless adequate versus inadequate
um lost versus having a vision and a
purpose
depending on the impressions that you
have
from your childhood or sometimes your
early
you know formative years if you've got
traumas as an adult
you're going to introject some of these
core
feelings and you're going to over
generalize them
to your situations so that
you know and i maybe i can even ask that
um how many of you people
you know how many of you out there have
realized that you
show up to relationships in a certain
way
and feel a certain way regardless of who
the person is or
very often or you feel a certain way
whenever money comes up
you know like that you've noticed that
there are feelings
involved and i've got some hands
okay wonderful and so what happens with
the bioemotive framework is you get a
very explicit
language for capturing those feeling
energies
into very obvious
categories that you can do something
with you can process
and start working on more explicitly and
more rationally than just
being subject to them it helps you
disidentify
and you can also clean it out from your
system and this will be
clearer to you once you do the
assessment okay so
i'm gonna just go through the five
critical stages now
and i guess to finish once you do the
assessment
you're gonna get an email back to you
highlighting one of the challenges that
you may be having
and and it's almost like an astrological
chart but it's just going to be based on
one
of your feelings not a but and it's
going to be a general thing people who
have the burden of
helplessness will often experience blah
blah blah blah blah blah
when they're trying to be an
entrepreneur people who have the burden
of
worthlessness will often find it
challenging to do the following right
so that's what you'll get back and um
i think doug is threatening us with this
article
playfully interesting i don't have time
to look at it but i'm glad it's
playfully
um so what i want you to do is look at
these stages
and i want you to
imagine what's involved in
doing that stage and how often
a feeling comes up when you think of
doing
that so the first stage is finding the
right business idea i'll overview the
stages first
developing a business plan raising your
seed funding getting paying customers
and then becoming a success or a failure
so that's some really broad categories
now what does it mean to find the right
business idea
you have to be creative insightful
have focus you have to have empathy
you know what do your potential
customers want even if they don't know
they want it and you have to be able to
imagine
a minimal viable product that you could
like start
testing out for viability
so when you think of that stage how many
people are at that stage of their
entrepreneurial business
where they're coming up with an idea and
for those of you who are
past it you know what was it like
you know like when i say you've got to
be creative and insightful
and have empathy how many people go
oh awesome that's me i can do that
okay i'm seeing about 30 40
of the hands how many people go oh
that's not what i have to offer this is
really hard for me
and and what's interesting if you're
doing that i wonder what it is that got
you into being an entrepreneur
because most people get excited by the
idea
right and and they they they they
push themselves to learn this thing to
bring the idea to fruition
so that's usually not the stumbling
block for most people
um does anyone want to share what it was
like to
think about being creative and
you know whether that was easy or
challenging and how they
got past that particular step
uh i'd like to share sure adam sure
um so i've had a
a few bursts in the last few years of
creative energy
and uh they happen
like like 18 months to two years apart
and each time it's almost like it's too
easy
i get really high on the energy and
i and i get really manic
and i'll do something silly like
buy a plane ticket that i
didn't need or buy a url
and start the whole like design process
i get really high on the creative
process
to my own destruction and this last
time around my wife really helped me
calm down and realize it and i'm
starting to approach everything from a
less manic
state now that's beautiful and that
actually
shows the potential drawback of the
creative process
when it can get overwhelming and take
control
and you basically lose perspective and
luckily your wife helped you keep
perspective and i would say that's a
first facet disidentification you can
recognize that energy and not get
carried away with it
the way you did in the past and so now
you can start
using it and channeling it the other
thing that i hear going on
is that you're not in control of when
those creative bursts
happen and and that's one of the things
about an
entrepreneurial world is that many of us
are we we wait for the creativity
and we don't realize that creativity
like many other dimensions of being can
be cultivated
and nurtured and made a little bit more
uh
conscious and explicit that you don't
have to be subject to the random
fluctuations of your creativity but you
can learn
to cultivate and nurture it like find
your muse
so to speak so that's a great example of
you know the pros and cons of you know
the first step
and if you don't have the creativity
it's often easy to just drop out of the
process
right there and why would you drop out
because you'd probably
feel something like hopelessness
right so i'm gonna just look at andrew
he had mentioned that he had trouble
with the creativity
is that a feeling that came up for you
on the entrepreneurial journey
oh yeah like with the hope
hopelessness like i i didn't want to be
an entrepreneur but i
like i don't want to like i i if
somebody said here's the thing do
exactly what you want to do um
go for it like that's what i want like
but i re
and then i'm i'm waking up and realizing
that that's not gonna happen
that i have to do this so that's where
i'm like i have to be
like responsible for myself and to get
business the way i want to do it is
going to have to be an entrepreneur
interesting and so
and to be fair i do i do stand-up comedy
and i've been doing it for like eight
years
and i don't wanna and i don't wanna wait
for people to
i don't wanna i don't want to go to
festivals and
and network and be this authentic
and i want to like so there's like a
there's a crate
there's stuck being creative
in the business sense
right right and that's where
it's easy to get overwhelmed and to feel
hopeless
especially if you don't have an explicit
structure
that you can feel empowers you to get to
where you want to
if you're making it up as opposed to
taking advantage of all the people who
have been there before you
it's easy to get overwhelmed in those
first steps
if you realize that you can hire a guide
and help you through those steps because
they've gone through it
you can save yourself a lot of pain and
suffering
but to do that you have to have
interpersonal skills and sense of
self-efficacy
and a feeling of potency and believe in
yourself and have enough self-worth that
you can contact people and put that kind
of money on and you can see how
immediately all your emotional issues
start getting
you know activated and this shows up at
every stage so we're going to move on to
developing a business plan and i wish
i could read this and see your faces at
the same time because
and maybe i can to really develop a
business plan and this is something
where i find
a lot of people skip you have to be
systematic and analytical and ideally
mathematically inclined
so that you can sit down with a
spreadsheet
and post your potential sales by
potential product
prices get a sense of the costs you know
for the product the infrastructure costs
the employee costs the taxes
you know and it's it can be pretty
overwhelming to do that kind of
assessment
especially if you're going to start
playing with that as variables to see
well where are the thresholds by which i
need to you know charge so
when i talk about doing this kind of
analysis for developing
a business plan how many people get
excited and how many people find
themselves
falling away from this
part of their journey how many people
i'm noticing nathan is laughing do you
want to share a little bit here
nathan on what what this means to you it
just
incites like a deep panic in me a
democratic
yeah it's just like so overwhelming the
idea of like
figuring out this really complicated uh
mathematical like charting out what's
possible what's going to happen and
taking all these factors into account
and i just like
just like i just want to make stuff
i don't i don't want to do this
assessment
and yet if you don't do this right
you're screwed because i've watched
people bring products
to the marketplace only to realize that
they can't
charge enough to make it worth their
time
they didn't do the cost estimates you
know and they put a lot of time and
energy into it
you know i've i've invested in a company
called three guys greens
and we did spreadsheets and i actually
love statistics and mathematics and
spreadsheets and
programming so i wrote you know variable
functions and looking at thresholds and
finding optimal things
and we bought the equipment based on
that
and then found out that they messed up
on their estimates of the production of
the equipment we bought
and it completely blew our business plan
right so we had to scramble and actually
build our equipment
you know uh by scratch almost from
in an ad hoc way not the same
quality as they they delivered to us but
we saved a lot because we understood the
process at that time
and we've now brought our production
levels back up to what they should have
been
but like it almost destroyed our
business because those estimates weren't
accurate but
it wasn't our fault right and and a lot
of people
just ignore that piece and hope it goes
away or hope they're successful it's
like well
i'll build a good enough product that it
doesn't matter
right it'll just bring in the money and
i don't
have to worry about you know my my
margins like that
that's usually not true how many people
have got that
sense that it doesn't matter i'm just
going to build a good enough product
that i don't have to worry about margins
per se
it could be true it could be true but
often you have to be very aware of it
because as soon as you start getting
successful
you have to hire people to do things to
keep up with the volumes and
got to make sure that you can afford to
do that and still keep
you know price points competitive uh
michael you wanted to share something
uh yeah um there's uh
so i i have a very mathematical mind i
used to do this kind of work for
a company that i built with some other
people in california so i'm very
familiar with this dimension
um but a trouble that i run into is at
least in my mind and in my my
sort of energetic emotional experience
that kind of thinking is antithetical to
the creative process
i can sort of get momentum on one or the
other
but there's a clear trade-off between
them on the time scale
of days and weeks so i'm wondering if
like if you've encountered this and if
so do you have a way to
navigate that so you're saying that when
you're in a creative mode you can't
access the mathematical capacities and
vice versa
uh it's kind of it's it's more like uh i
can look at the
i can look look at the spreadsheets and
the planning and i can see how the math
works and i can see ah and then
this can appeal to this market and here
and very very analytic
thinking about how the whole thing works
and then if the energy the sort of
emotional tone that i use for that
thinking
is still in me when i turn towards
how i'm going to
interact with people or what kind of
products i'm going to put together
there's almost it's almost like there's
a functional exploitative
way of operating that dominates the
frame
that's antithetical to the thing that
i'm trying to create
but if i get into sort of the the more
interpersonal
open relational dimension of oh this is
what i want to make this is what i want
to cause in the world this is what i
really care about
i find that it's very hard to
um it's like the spreadsheets feel like
they're adding blades to my gut
it's just not it doesn't fit
yeah so it's what's beautiful is that
you're
depicting in one person what i hear in
often in separate people
you know that they've got one modality
or the other and they can't switch back
and forth and you're lucky you can
switch
but they are different parts of our
neural substrates
and and um they do seem sometimes to
be inhibitory i know when i'm doing a
lot of statistical work
it's a really hard for me to sit down
and write a report on a client
my the brain tissues just aren't there
and i've learned that i have to take
some time to prime myself
to slowly nurture my brain into that
world
so i've consciously kind of created some
metacognitive
programs or instructions for myself that
prime my brain into thinking a certain
way
right for me i can easily move between
the creative
and the mathematical statistical because
i find statistical mathematical stuff
extremely creative so they're very much
in the same world
but as soon as i have to deal with
writing about interpersonal dynamics
and i'm in that brain it just doesn't
work i have to what i find is i sit down
and i'll just read a report that i've
written already
in the past and that starts those
neurons firing
and then i can certainly move into that
world and start writing
that's a disidentification process first
facet
that i can name the thing instead of
just getting caught in it
and moving into a depression or a
hopelessness because my mind isn't there
thank you so i'm going to um
i hope that's helpful you know i'm i'm
i'm weaving in a lot of
other things besides the emotional stuff
but um
let's move on to raising your seed
funding and this is
often challenging um how many people are
just trying to do it with their own
money and time and how many people are
actually needing to
ask for money you know
how many people are asking for money
because if you ask for money you've got
to go to relatives or investors
and i don't see anybody raising their
hand for
asking for money does that mean that
everybody's fairly independently wealthy
and just have their the finances to
to pay for everything you need here
i have a conflict on that point uh
by trying to do something that could be
a like a tech startup and
raise funds in the traditional way i
convinced myself that it would be better
to
to develop in open source and
trust the community to provide based on
the value they see
in the product and this is a core
question
i'm wondering if i retreated into that
because i'm too afraid of
asking for money
that's a wonderful question to have and
i think a really important one because
if you're if you're going to the social
commons and the social good
and assuming it will turn into
fiscal you know reimbursement
i think peter actually went through that
stage peter you you had uh
a quote that you passed on to us a while
ago do you remember what it was
no i don't remember oh it was something
to the effect of
[Music]
just because you're producing
a high-end like socially responsible
program
doesn't mean you'll actually make enough
money to
to support it and but there was a twist
in it because the money thing was in the
in the earlier part of the
phrase but it it caught the same dilemma
here that that
often uh the vision that we have for
social responsibility doesn't touch the
same people and produce the same
outcomes as
you know an explicitly fiscal
reimbursement model some of the open
source things make a lot of money
and some of them don't and and uh you
know you can do that investigation
um let's suppose you had to ask
for money you get to a point where you
have to ask for money
how many people would feel fine doing
that
pitching yourself you know at a
one of those dens you know the uh
those entrepreneurial kind of one-minute
pitches
like is everybody comfortable standing
up in front of somebody and pitching
their idea
to get enthusiasm and money is that
something you can do easily
we've got andrew who's pretty
comfortable in front of people
and i'm not seeing other people saying
they're that comfortable
and if you're not what are you
feeling when you think about having to
pitch your idea in front of people
it's probably not a positive feeling so
does someone want to share what that
might be
what are you feeling when you think
about having to pitch i can
i can go yeah so like there's a pressure
in my chest right here it's almost like
something's digging in or pushing in um
if i were to tease out some words from
that
it's just kind of like um
feeling of being a burden
potentially um
[Music]
yeah and then and then um making things
more difficult for people and stuff like
that like there's a bunch of adjacent
things going on there
so if i approach someone with my idea
i'm just gonna burden them
and and it'll be a nuisance for them and
i'll be bothering them
right and this is on the
directly translating the the motions
this is not really propositional
yeah yeah nice nice
um sarah's saying i'm feeling on the
hook
for something uh interesting
so if you ask for money you'll owe them
something
kind of thing which would be i would
imagine entrepreneurial success
um we're gonna move on and i'm gonna
just
read out some of the other stages so to
get paying customers
you have to find who has an itch or a
pain or a need that your
product scratches relieves fulfills
build an email list
you know with intriguing and valuable
giveaways
use facebook and google advertising to
hone in on your
tribe keep track of analytics and bounce
rates and click rates and democrat
demographics who is your tribe who's
responding
cold calls to people you don't know to
see if they're interested in this
thing you've made for chiropractors or
for
or you know people doing herbal healing
um what's it feel like
when i list these things off building an
email list
you know using facebook and keeping
track of analytics and bounce rates
to the extent that you have an emotional
reaction
that isn't positive and enthusiastic
you've got a little bit of a feeling
belief or a limitation in your system
and then the last thing about you're
either a successor of a failure
i've i've been around a lot of
entrepreneurs over the last 10 years
and i've watched them struggle and
fail and struggle again and fail
and on the third or the fourth time they
make it
it's very rare for someone to make it
the first time
and the the overnight successes that we
see have usually been around for five to
ten years
but you didn't notice them because they
were failing all the time
so if you fail what's your emotional
response to that
is it hopelessness and resignation
you know and if it's not or if it is
what do you do to overcome it
so what's someone's response to failure
who's actually tried something and
failed
and still got up to go again david do
you want to share
what it was like for you yeah i'm
actually
right in the middle of that so i was uh
teaching yoga and meditation and
regularly and was going well
and then govit happened and i switched
to um making it online you know
and at first that went well and now it's
like um
a plateau no new people are
signing up anymore in the past weeks
were like
should i stop and i kind of overcame it
like yesterday
when i um was talking to my wife just
you know blabbering
and said yeah i just have to go back to
why i'm doing this
you know i'm very enthusiastic about
meditating every day i'm just going to
go back and share that
no matter what happens next so i'm at
that right now
okay so when you realized it wasn't
going and you know what was the
feeling that you had yeah the feelings
there was doubt you know who am i to
teach meditation
so inadequacy i guess and also feeling
stuck you know hopeless like i've been
really trying the past months it's not
really
going anywhere but then came detour the
thought of yeah
i did not do all these steps that i
planned because of this hopelessness and
then i got
new energy like yeah i will just try
again
okay so what your your outlining is
i'm going to turn your mute you because
you're there's a bounce back
he he just did a great sharing of
feeling
hopeless and feeling inadequate
and the fact that he could name them
gives you some distance from them and
he's in my nadura group so i know he's
gone through this
and and he's felt this you don't take
your emotions and feelings as seriously
when you can name them it takes a while
but you'll start having them as
feelings as opposed to being who you are
and then what he did is we went back to
his original
vision and re-stimulated his purpose
so that it could kind of override and
re-enthusiast
re recreate the enthusiasm he had for
why he was doing it it's easy
to lose track of your vision which gives
you the energy and the purpose
when you get caught in these other
emotions of hopelessness and inadequacy
and who am
i to do these kinds of things so
we've just overviewed enough of this
that i'm going to share
in the chat to everybody
an assessment that it'll probably take
about 10 minutes to do
and it will give you a really personal
insight
to you and the particular
challenges that you have
i'm going to read it through let's go
through it together okay
so pop it up on your screen by
completing
this form you have the opportunity to
discover which core feeling impressions
in your system are causing
unconscious distress and possibly
creating barriers to your success
peter do you like my banner up there
isn't that sweet
i love it yeah
when you begin the next session use the
sentence stem
that feels most comfortable such as i
feel or sometimes or feel or sometimes a
part of me feels
and you want to say it out loud this
process is less about the details and
the facts and more about trying to
access the feelings hitting away inside
you
which nonetheless have great influences
over your actions
and your sense of who you are and
remember that
feelings are not rational so try not to
let your
intellect interfere with your
experiencing of the
feelings i talk about the triune brain
the intellect the emotional brain and
the physical brain
they can all process the same reality
very differently we tend to bias the
intellect
and let it dominate but the emotional
brain is
actually what's running the show most of
the time it's the thing that we're using
our intellectual willpower
to overcome we don't want to keep doing
that we want to
tune in and honor the emotional system
and process it
so that we can work with the feelings
directly
now processing feelings can be upsetting
especially if you're not used to it
don't do this if you're feeling fragile
okay i don't think this is the case for
you guys
you can also just distance yourself or
stop if you get too deeply triggered
everything here is confidential it's
going to be collected for me
and i'm going to continue doing data
analysis on it but um
it will never be shared with your names
on it in fact i
that gets stripped off from the data
that i do analyzing
so if you put your email address in
there that's the only mandatory
thing and that's that i can send you the
results put in your name or an alias
and then just get a sense of you know
when you see
you know how much do you see your fears
and psychological issues as barriers to
your success
right now and just get a sense like i'm
talking about how important is it but
how real
is it for you how aware is it and
and maybe you don't have many fears and
psychological issues
so you don't have to put it high but if
you do and you can see the impact
just try and get a sense of them and
then how direct how committed are you to
directly find and face those barriers
in order to be successful and this was a
really informative set of questions for
us to look at who was actually
successful
in doing this work in becoming you know
successful entrepreneurs
so go on to the next one
i want you to think i don't have it here
i want you to think of a particular
barrier that you're having
okay and and it's not rational but see
if you can like
articulate it in a sentence like i'm
having a trouble
phoning people to get interest or to see
if they want to buy my product or
um i'm having trouble coming up with
whatever it is your barrier is
and once you find it
ask yourself you know in that context
sometimes a part of me feels
very alone and just rate how much
activation you get
right maybe the whole entrepreneurial
enterprise you feel very alone
and and makes you sad but it's a
sacrifice you're willing to do
in order to gain that that success but
you're still sad that you're not going
to work every day
and meeting with colleagues and other
people who don't have the same pressures
sometimes a part of me feels very
inadequate
and just let your body emotional system
see how it responds to that situation
i feel inadequate that means i'm not
really prepared
to do this i could if i spent the time
but i'm not prepared
or i feel very insignificant
i don't want to bother people i don't
want to take up their time
they wouldn't notice me anyway
sometimes a part of me feels very lost
or i feel
lost when i get to this point
i feel helpless 0 to ten
sometimes a part of me feels very
worthless or
i feel worthless
if you feel worthless it'll be really
hard for you to take anyone's time
to ask for resources to spend the money
that you need to get the training
that you need to do this
this one a deep emptiness
it can be loss but generally if it's
been around a long time it's experienced
as an emptiness
and in this context that's how we've got
it so
a feeling of loss that doesn't resolve
over time will often become a feeling of
emptiness or a hole in your heart
or the positive feeling once lived
and see if there's a sense of emptiness
maybe you lost a partner
in this and you've never quite gotten
over it
you feel abandoned or alone right and
there's an emptiness
it doug yeah i might have missed
you saying this um do we focus on this
question that's surrounded like
entrepreneurialism
uh or just in general because i'm having
different things come up
well yeah and so i i didn't have you
write it down but this should be in a
specific context where you feel a block
in your entrepreneurial success where
you're you're definitely
challenged right now and it'll be
different for everybody
okay this is an old form and the new
ones have a space
for placing the context so you'll just
have to remember in your head what this
is
this other one i feel like a bad person
you know i shouldn't do that
um it wouldn't be right to interrupt
the ceo from his day he's a busy man
and i would be bad to do that
or it's bad to make money you know and
there's a block that comes up
some people have very negative
associations to money
um a part of me feels very hopeless
when this scenario comes up
and then there's a space for any other
feelings
the nine core feelings will get them but
there might be interpersonal feelings
that you can list here
and then these other ones you can answer
or not they were useful for us
you know when you wake up in the morning
how often do you feel refreshed relaxed
and alert
you know i would put a 10 on that that's
i'm i assume that everybody felt like
that for the longest time and then i
realized
they don't uh some people are always at
a two or a three but that makes a big
difference on
how likely you are to succeed if you're
not waking up with
a good pool of physical energy
it's hard to be emotionally successful
or emotionally engaged
how relaxed are you most of the time
if it's not at all you know uh it's
going to be challenging and that
actually showed up
on um on our entrepreneurial things is
that successful entrepreneurs were not
anxious and did not have a lot of fear
whereas a lot of the
aspiring entrepreneurs had a lot of
anxiety and fear
and that was something they had to work
on when you're faced with a conflict by
between yourself and another person
do you tend to get angry sad fearful
anxious agitated tense
or do you kind of move towards
calm and peace it's probably too extreme
to say complete common piece but
most people will move in
one of those directions the
more emotional ones are clearer if it's
body agitation and things you're having
emotions and tensions and stuff
that you're not aware of the emotional
stuff and that's that's okay that's just
where you are
right now and hopefully you'll start
waking up to the emotional energies
um how would you rank yourself in terms
of relating to emotions and feelings
not at all connected as a one in ten as
you you feel and embrace them
completely uh this is actually pretty
important
uh for long-term health is how often do
you cry
you know when you need to if you're
crying all the time that's probably
not good if you're crying when you need
to maybe once a week or once a month
depending on your life
that's probably a good sign if you
haven't cried for years
or since you're a young child that
either means you've led a blessed life
or you've got a lot of repression
those will be obstacles to your success
how what are your feelings about
finances right now
and what's your biggest motivation for
pursuing the path of an entrepreneur
i want financial freedom i want to be
rich you know and not have to work for
anyone so it's more about a post-modern
quality of life
a modern i want to be rich i want status
and recognition
i feel my products and services will
benefit the world
i want more time with my family i want
more time to pursue my interests i want
to be able to travel the world while
making money
or other and it's really good to know
why you're doing this
if you haven't thought about it if this
is not easy um
spend some time with it and then
this is if you guys are interested this
isn't a commitment
uh how interested are you in attending a
four-hour seminar where we go into
detail and depth uh for 97
us dollars i can put a seminar together
if there's enough interest
and then while you're doing this did you
experience any emotional activation and
this isn't necessarily the context for
that
but when you're doing this alone and
you're spending time with a block with a
lot of charge you might
find that this is true you can use this
form more than once you can keep the
link
and then any comments or anything you'd
like to share so once you hit
submit you're going to get a form sent
to you
now i had said to peter that we'd go for
an hour hour and a half
this was registered as 60th minute
we're going to probably take another 10
to 20 minutes to to complete this i'm
going to review
some of the feedback that you're going
to get okay so hit submit
and then check your inbox and you're
going to get
um some feedback based on
the prevalent core emotion that showed
up for you
in as you did this and what i'm going to
do
is read my little summaries of those
the people
yeah so just
check your inbox and make sure that you
get your uh
your email if you need
okay so what's going to happen now
is i'm going to read
and we're going to sort of share a
little bit uh you you'll take take a few
minutes now to read
the response that you got
and uh see how it resonates for you
someone's asking if there's particular
postures or positions to make it easier
to feel the feelings
in general you want to be as relaxed as
you can
right so whatever that means for me that
means in a half lotus
with a little bit of support on my lower
back and that's the most relaxing
position i can be in for the people who
are saying i'm needing more time to
resonate
with the statements that's fine you can
do this again
uh but likely one of them will
feel more true and you can just respond
to that if you do it again and something
else resonates then
read what that's like
so let me just
pull that up now
so we're gonna look how many people got
a
um a
core feeling of inadequacy
if you just put up your hands okay so
i'm gonna read this out and i want you
to share with me what it
how true it feels
entrepreneurs who carry the burden of
inadequacy
often feel like they don't have the
skills or qualifications to succeed in
their vision
and are prone to under charge for their
services
they can get stuck at the dreaming stage
of being an entrepreneur and never move
beyond it
if they get their businesses going they
never feel like they've accomplished
enough
and tend to overwork themselves to
compensate for feeling and not
inadequate often not damaging their
personal relationships
so people relate to that the people who
got that
is there any truth there that you'd like
to just share a little bit
of anything that lands on you as you
hear that
yeah andy i feel a
um inadequacy based on
incoherence meaning not being incoherent
with
the fact that
my business is kind of zero-sum
or excuse me yeah zero sum competitive
transactional based in some ways game a
kind of thinking
and i would like to move my professional
and
personal life to more of a game b
collaborative
space so um i think
i can shift the business um
with some new heuristics to that
um but i'm feeling like the coherence
isn't ideal because
i'm not sure that the service provided
is when you have the transactional
component
it complicates things so i mean i guess
in other words it
kind of
how do you uh suggest that
entrepreneurs um who have
um transactional based businesses or
that have to become transactional to
some degree to make a living
how do you cohere that with this
collaborative structure because
at some point do you get more clients
do you make more money well here here's
where
i think what you're there's an
inadequacy possibly in your
inability to have formed an inadequate
vision
for this endeavor so in the three guys
greens venture that i mentioned we're a
class b
corporation which means we have social
responsibility
and so we give portions of our harvest
every week
to um agencies that are supporting the
poor and the homeless
and um you know we're contributing
to society in that sense in my own
biomotive process where i'm trying to be
socially responsible a lot of my
programs are pay what you can
if you go to my monthly subscriptions
you can get into my new group for as low
as eighty dollars
and the recommended fee is is 180.
you know same with the circling um often
if you approach us
and say you know i need some help we'll
work something out so there's that
social responsibility so we've
come up with a vision that we feel
marries the transactional with the
social
and that took some time to develop um
karen hargrave has a great book
out there called pay what you can and i
know um
vincent horn's doing that with his uh
his teaching as well
so it just takes some creativity and
ingenuity
but it does take time for your specific
situation
okay um so thanks for the question i
hope that was helpful
i'm thinking instead of
me going through each of them does
people want to just share
any strong feelings that came up as they
went through the program anything that
surprised them
and then i'll either read the the you
know the blurb
or we'll just interact on it in a way
that might be helpful
so who had any some strong or surprising
feelings that came up when they
went through the core feelings
assessment on the particular issue they
were
trying to work with
how about moderate feelings
i had
you know what uh i'll let stephen
stephen talk okay
yes stephen
are you going to speak okay
sorry someone else speaking yeah
uh yeah i had a question um you
mentioned loss
can we distinguish that from lost
feeling a sense of loss seems different
than being lost a bit of confused or
overwhelmed how would you distinguish
this who or where's the overlap
oh very very very different feelings um
loss means you once had a positive
feeling experience
and it could be anything the sense of
significance connection and cared for
um value were you know worth and then
you lost it so if you were the most
valuable player on the basketball team
and broke your leg
you'd feel a huge loss of no longer
feeling valued
and you might also feel lost
because you no longer have a vision that
you can enact
that brings meaning to your life but
they're very
separate dimensions if you if you don't
have a vision
you will be lost so andy is an example
of
trying to marry two things that seem
opposite
and he has no vision that can allow him
to move forward so he's lost
he doesn't know how to make sense of his
world in a way that he can be
constructive
okay i guess in my case it's it's more
the loss
i think i have much greater sense of
meaning than i did before
with say an earlier successful
entrepreneurial venture ventures but
it's
a lot more confusing
to get those ideas into something that
is a
you know the right business model just
choosing that or the right target market
and all those things
that yeah
but it's more emotional than uh then i
you know i
i've talked to you know that my you know
rich network and the you know
the startup ecosystem they're they're
not helping
i don't feel like i get the right help
it's uh
yeah it's i i relate
to the feeling lost and not knowing who
your target audience is
and one of the reasons or one of the
things i've really come to appreciate
for straight entrepreneurial success
is the sas model software as a solution
where you go and find somebody who has a
huge need
and is willing to pay for it and then
you develop a solution
you're guaranteed customers and you can
often get startup money to build
the the solution we
tend to do it the opposite where we feel
passionate about a solution and then we
hope
to find people who have that problem and
convince them that we have a wonderful
solution for them
when i first put out my dvds on the
emotional biomotor framework
10 plus years ago i just assumed it was
so wonderful and
and great and resonant that people would
you know come
stomping to my door to buy it and then i
just realized oh that's not how it works
right and i've worked with entrepreneurs
i've worked
you know and it turns out the people
that seem to meditate
or people who have been hanging out
mostly with me lately that
are advanced meditators and people
committed to a personal transformational
path
um i'd love to work with golfers i
haven't found a niche in there yet
i haven't found a way to resonate with
them but as i move towards retirement
i'm probably going to find a way to work
with them but for right now i'm lost
and and uh feeling a little inadequate
and sometimes helpless because the
the routes that i have tried have failed
and i'm just so you know
it's a dance between what you who you
can serve and who
shows up to be served right that's often
what
what you end up with until you're
successful enough that you get to be a
little bit more picky and you have
enough
people coming that you can you know
choose your tribe more explicitly
so so thanks steven i hope that was
helpful
um andrew did you want to share
something or anyone else but we'll go
with andrew
i if somebody has something i'll just
say quick i was really shocked
and not so shocked but it was like oh my
core feeling was alone
like it was i could i was in sales
i could sell somebody else's product
and i there's that feeling like a bad
guy part
where i quit but if it's on myself
i don't it's hard like that's definitely
a block it was
eye-opening because it was like oh i
have i failed and i had resentment
because i was working with other people
having that pure confidence on my own is
super difficult
i think wow and and you know andrew even
as you're sharing that i can feel
the emotional reality that you've lived
through something
painful and that it unpacks into even
more
trauma in a sense where you feel
betrayed or something by other people or
let down
and literally that kind of emotional
energy
that's showing up into your
entrepreneurial world
is hindering your progress
oh yeah and so you know the bioemotive
framework gives you tools just finding
the core feelings
sitting with it saying i feel alone
find the interpersonal feelings like i
feel abandoned
or i feel betrayed and cry about it
you'll allow your emotional system to
update
and meet the reality that your intellect
knows to be true but that your emotional
system can't access right now and once
it does
you'll feel a shift and you won't
feel the aloneness in the same way and
the betrayal and abandonment won't
be there and you'll be able to step into
new opportunities without that fear and
ptsd type
encounter and probably learn to trust
people and embrace potential partners
that are showing up
but you unconsciously turn away from
because of this issue of
being alone and betrayed
so i'm speaking with general er general
rarity
but i'm seeing some of it resonating so
i'm hoping that you can
spend some time processing that on your
own oh yeah i'm working with a therapist
and that's definitely a
uh that's definitely themes that are
coming in and that's how i'm
like that's how i'm not like breaking
out in tears right now
but like yeah yeah awesome well waited
way to go andrew i admire
i admire that you're bringing that to
your to your world like that
and uh yeah anyone else want to share
some feelings that came up or surprised
them or that you're
you know had an interesting insight on
i wanted to share sure
um i'm not sure how coherent it becomes
when it gets translated to words
um well i'll pause you there the whole
point of the bible motive framework is
nadura
teaches you that it's not easy to put
words
to these feelings but there's a process
for doing it
and when you do it feels really good so
if you stumble around it means you're at
a leading edge
and it's an important thing so take your
time to find the words
and check for the resonance as you speak
you know follow the energy
the the feeling that's coming to mind is
there's a quote by jiddu krishnamurthy
um
it's not a sign of good health to be
adjusted to a profoundly sick society
and i have this feeling sometimes when
we're like i hate marketing or
oh it's so icky like what's wrong with
me
i feel in so many ways it's like it's
really sad that we'll
put it on to the person when it's
actually
the systems that we have here it's like
humans are meant to have
relationships they're about reciprocity
and
um supposed to be close and it's like
these are artificial
these relationships over distance and
these caricatures
that based off marketing and so i wonder
if one of the strengths
of this work is
in learning your personal
feelings that you're avoiding and
having more consciousness about that
does that allow you to have
more independence in recognizing these
things about the kind of sickness of the
world
like i feel like if um if i could share
what an example
like when it comes to raising money
it almost feels like it's hard to make
comments
about molok like the actual act of
raising money
causes so many of the problems because
you feel like you have to promise growth
you feel like you have to
say we're going to be this big we're
going to do all of that
um and it's almost like
it's hard to talk about that when in
undoubtedly there's all these feelings
about rejection
and fear um
so i'm just curious like whether that's
maybe one of the main benefits
of this work is you can actually realize
what's externally up um well
i'm gonna i'm gonna give you an edge
you probably don't like um
but if it doesn't fit or give you any
insights then you can just
let it go part of what i hear
um you is i'm hearing a i think a bit of
a
trauma-based bias of a vision for the
world
and like right now we're very much in a
modernist
developmental stage as a culture we've
grown out of traditional as a main
stay but there's a lot of people there
and we've certainly
gone out of for the most part the
dominance hierarchies
ideally we would all be at the
postmodern stage that you're talking
about but that takes time to get there
the modern stage that you're i think
having a lot of negative associations to
has
actually brought a lot of um
people out of poverty and improved the
standard of living
for many many beings around the world
and you can't you know and until they've
got those basic survival needs and
dynamics in place it's hard to relate
to a lot of these higher order
dimensions of
the quality of life and relationship
even though it was there in the past it
didn't have the technological
sophistication and and um
uh opportunities and and
perks that we have now in in the modern
world
so there's there's
strengths and weaknesses to each stage
but integral theory says that we all
have to move through the stages and we
just need to
try and be as healthy as we can
um your
feelings about raising money and the
fear of rejection
um it may be that you haven't found your
tribe
that you're trying to sell to the wrong
people
if you look at marketing closely and
this is something i admire
todd hargrave for he very much pushes
point of view marketing which is really
where you share some of your deeper
perspectives on how the world works and
what's important
and those people come to you and so
marketing becomes
a relational dynamic if you're speaking
your truth
in a way that honors you and your
potential tribe
they will hear you and resonate with you
and they will be just as enthusiastic as
you are
by your projects but if you're pitching
your um idea and vision to the wrong
people the wrong developmental stage or
in the wrong context you're just going
to get discord and friction
so you kind of have to ask yourself why
you're in that situation and
why you're not looking for a different
tribe or a set of funders because i know
they exist
like we're a class b corporation and
there's lots of people who have
those values that are also looking to
invest money
in places where they can make the world
a better place
so there's a lot there and i don't know
if i'm
i'm even going to leave you time to
respond because there's so much
um there but if you want to just say you
know
one or two things then we'll move on and
hopefully some of what i've said was
helpful
uh before you jump in anjon i just want
to flake that we have seven minutes
uh and then another session starts we
might get kicked out of this one
i'll try to be quick then doug um so a
lot of the
stuff we talk about at the stoa is this
the world today's got this particular
game theory
game a and it's kind of a downward
spiral in so many ways what malloc
is and it doesn't need to be that way if
the operating system
for society could be different there's
potentially ways to align interest have
an upward spiral game b and i think what
i'm reacting to is this idea that
like all of these engagements does have
so many personal feelings
but it's like so much is lost if you're
if you're only going to focus
on the personal feelings and not see the
methods of fundraising
cause so many misincentives like in
silicon valley
there's a lot of good people but they do
all these weird things because of the
way they raise money and things like
that
so i'm just trying to it feels like it
would be a loss to just
put it onto like personal feelings and
not recognize
the messed upness of these systems
yeah and and i'll i'll acknowledge that
and i'll also say that
there is a a reason
why they are the way they are there's
very complex factors and systems and
we need to learn to surf the waves that
are here not the waves that we want
uh otherwise we won't be able to get
anywhere and
um you know one of the things that i've
heard recently
um that i really appreciate is if
if people are gonna focus on the
a dysfunctional part of our culture and
do a lot of reading
and spending time talking about it and
they're not dedicating a part of their
life to fixing it
you're probably just hurting yourself
you know
that that there's a focus that that
we're we're just aggravating ourselves
by
like i stopped paying attention to
certain types of dysfunction in the
government
because it became really clear in my
mind that
you know it had been corrupted in many
ways
but me just seeing that over and over
and over just hurt
unless i was willing to spend some time
trying to do something and start
lobbying and
you know and i only have so much power
and energy and attention
i had to just drop it and go well that's
just the way it is and i'm glad
other people are looking after that
right now you know
one of the other things that i like
about the interpretation of the word
dharma is it means the way things are
and if you if you want to reduce
suffering you need to like
really acknowledge the way things are
do what you can to change them but also
realize
how big or little of an impact you can
have on it
and and just come to peace with the fact
that these are really big
systems that will take more than usually
more than one individual's
energy to change their systemic forces
that will take
usually decades not days or years
to to grow and once you realize that and
make peace with it
you know life gets gets a little bit
easier and you find ways to be
successful in
in ways that honor your values and not
cause
necessary suffering for yourself
thanks for listening to that and i hope
it's helpful and um
you know i'm just sharing kind of what
i've gone through and
what i resonate with what you're saying
anyone else have anything before we
close here
sarah why don't you share something
um well i i found
a wonderful feeling at first i'm just on
this video call
which was uh inadequate but then another
one came up of
bad which was more like um it's i'm
doing coaching and like
oh what if someone says i've done i've
done it wrong i've been unethical and
there's no
structure to support me in or support a
resolution
remediation that oh it feels awful
family stuff
terrible wow
okay so that's something you'll continue
kind of unpacking and working with
nice well i hope this was helpful i hope
this has given you a whole
different approach to understanding some
of the blocks you face as entrepreneurs
my experience is that the more aware we
are of our emotional realities
and the more conscious we are about
processing
our feelings and our lived experiences
the
easier and happier and more flowing our
life becomes
and it also helps a lot with our
developmental stages
and the entrepreneurial path that you've
chosen
is a very powerful path because if you
continue it
you will just keep bumping up against
your
feelings of inadequacy and all the other
feelings that
you need to work on because they're
probably not true but you've been living
with them a long time
and they feel true to you you know and
uh if you do the work and keep pushing
towards your goal
you will be successful even if it means
failing many times
you know until you find a product that
resonates and sells so
i wish you all great luck good luck and
success and and happy processing guys
i hope i hope it's good for you uh
and can i plug something uh before you
head out
um hey i really want to plug doug's uh
practice uh i had a session with his
daughter last week it was really really
awesome
uh and this like i kind of geek out
about all these psycho
therapeutic frameworks we're gonna have
like a psychotherapy a psychotherapeutic
cafe here at the stoa where we're gonna
look at stuff like
acceptance commitment therapy gestalt
focusing and this one is
my favorite right now so highly
recommend checking it out and doug
i'd love to have you back at the stoa
well thanks it's always fun to
to do this peter and i and i really
appreciate the vision that you're
embodying and bringing forth into the
world it's just it's beautiful to see
how quickly
you're bringing in big names and you
know wonderful experiences for us
so congrats thank you um
and uh yeah there's something out if you
do you have like two minutes after this
to chat
uh yeah okay so i'll send you a
different zoom link um
uh but that being said doug everyone
thanks so much for coming to show today
thank you